import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData: ExamData = {
  title: "Gas Turbine Engines",
  questions: [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "When gases pass through a convergent duct their:",
      "options": [
        "velocity and temperature increase and their pressure decreases",
        "their velocity increases and their temperature and pressure decrease",
        "their velocity decreases and their temperature and pressure increase",
        "they expand adiabatically"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Select the correct order of best propulsive efficiency, from low to high airspeed.",
      "options": [
        "High bypass ratio turbojet, Low bypass ratio turbojet, Pure turbojet, Turboprop",
        "Low bypass ratio turbojet, Pure turbojet, Turboprop, High bypass ratio turbojet",
        "Pure turbojet, Turboprop, High bypass ratio turbojet, Low bypass ratio turbojet",
        "Turboprop, High bypass ratio turbojet, Low bypass ratio turbojet, Pure turbojet"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "The highest pressure in a gas turbine engine occurs:",
      "options": [
        "between the compressor and the combustion chamber",
        "in the combustion chamber",
        "in the jet pipe",
        "at the P1 probe"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "In a turbofan engine, the fan speed is controlled by:",
      "options": [
        "a reduction gear",
        "a wastegate",
        "the turbine",
        "varying the pitch"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "In a High Bypass Ratio engine:",
      "options": [
        "all of the air goes through both the low and high pressure compressors",
        "not all the air goes through the high pressure compressor",
        "not all the air goes through the low pressure compressor",
        "all the air goes through the high pressure compressor"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Modular construction:",
      "options": [
        "is only used on turboprop engines",
        "cannot be used on high ratio engines",
        "has a weight saving function",
        "enables malfunctioning sections of the engine to be changed without changing the whole engine"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "The Bypass Ratio of an engine is the ratio of:",
      "options": [
        "primary air to tertiary air",
        "cold stream air to that flowing through the hot core of the engine",
        "exhaust gas pressure to air intake pressure",
        "primary air to secondary air"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "The Gas Turbine Engine uses the principle of:",
      "options": [
        "Newtonâ€™s Third Law of motion",
        "creating thrust equal to the weight of the aircraft",
        "expelling air at the same speed as that of the aircraft",
        "the fluid flywheel"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The addition of heat in a combustion chamber allows a:",
      "options": [
        "large expansion at a substantially constant pressure",
        "large expansion at a constant volume",
        "large expansion at a decreasing static pressure",
        "minimum expansion at a constant volume"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "In a divergent duct:",
      "options": [
        "the pressure decreases and the temperature and velocity increases",
        "the pressure, velocity and temperature increases",
        "the pressure temperature increases and the velocity decreases",
        "the pressure decreases, the temperature increases and the velocity remains constant"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "In a twin spool engine:",
      "options": [
        "the LP compressor is connected to the HP compressor",
        "the HP turbine is connected to the LP compressor, the LP turbine is connected to the HP compressor",
        "the LP turbine is connected to the LP compressor, the HP turbine is connected to the HP compressor",
        "the HP turbine is connected to the LP turbine, the HP compressor is connected to the LP compressor"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "A Bypass Ratio of 5:1 means that:",
      "options": [
        "5 pounds of air is bypassed for every 10 pounds entering the engine intake",
        "5 pounds of goes through the HP compressor for every 10 pounds that enters the intake",
        "10 pounds of air goes through the bypass for every 5 pounds that enters the intake",
        "5 pounds of air is bypassed for every 1 pound that goes through the hot core of the engine"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "Aft of the compressor:",
      "options": [
        "the velocity of the airflow remains the same",
        "the velocity of the airflow decreases before the combustion chamber",
        "the velocity increases before the combustion chamber",
        "the air pressure decreases before the combustion chamber"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "The fan in a ducted fan engine, is driven by:",
      "options": [
        "the high pressure turbine",
        "the rearmost turbine",
        "the intermediate pressure turbine",
        "all of the above"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "In a bypass engine, the bypass air:",
      "options": [
        "increases the air mass flow and therefore increases the propulsive efficiency",
        "cools the combustion chamber and therefore increases the thermal efficiency",
        "reduces the air mass flow and therefore increases the propulsive efficiency",
        "increases the air mass flow and therefore reduces the propulsive efficiency"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "The majority of the thrust of a:",
      "options": [
        "turbofan engine comes from the turbine exhaust",
        "turboprop engine comes from the turbine exhaust",
        "turboshaft engine comes from the free power turbine exhaust",
        "turbofan engine comes from the bypass air"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "A pure turbojet engine gives:",
      "options": [
        "a small acceleration to a large mass of air",
        "a large acceleration to a large mass of air",
        "a small acceleration to a small mass of air",
        "a large acceleration to a small mass of air"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "During the Brayton cycle, combustion takes place:",
      "options": [
        "continuously",
        "once every revolution",
        "once every other revolution",
        "only during the start cycle"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    }
  ]
}
